Guide to the Pacific Improvement Company Records, 1901-1966 JL017
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- P.I. Co. Quitclaims, Documents - contains only duplicate documents re: quitclaims. Coded by numbers (probably) as received but not perfect chronologically. Documents are filed and files are marked according to document code numbers 100001 - 103266. Documents of all kinds, predominantly quitclaim d
  - “100701 to 100800”., Jan. - April 1918. (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - “100801 to 100900”., April - July 1918. (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - “100901 to 101000”., June - Oct. 1918. (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - “101001 to 101100”., Oct. 1918 - Jan. 1919. (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - “101101 to 101200”., Jan. - April 1919. (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - “101201 to 101300”., April - June 1919. (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - “101301 to 101400”., June - Sept. 1919. (Box 33, Folder 15)
  - “101401 to 101500”., Sept. - Nov. 1919. (Box 33, Folder 16)
  - “101501 to 101600”., Oct. 1919 to Jan. 1920. (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - “101601 to 101700”., Jan. - March 1920. (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - “101701 to 101800”., March - May 1920. (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - “101801 to 101900”., June - Oct. 1920. (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - “101901 to 102000”., Oct. 1920 - Feb. 1921. (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - “102001 to 102100”., Feb. - Sept. 1921. (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - “102101 to 102200”., Sept. 1921 - Feb. 1922. (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - “102201 to 102300”., Feb. - July 1922. (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - “102301 to 102500”., July 1922 - March 1923. (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - “102501 to 102600”., March - Dec. 1923. (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - “102601 to 102700”., Dec. 1923 - Dec. 1924. (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - “102701 to 102800”., Dec. 1924 - Dec. 1925. (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - “102801 to 102900”., Jan. 1926 to Feb. 1928. (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - “102901 to 103000”., March 1928 - Aug. 1935. (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - “103001 to 103100”., Oct. 1935 - Aug. 1942. (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - “103101 to 103200”., April 1943 - April 1953. (Box 34, Folder 16)
  - “103201 to 103266”., May 1953 - July 1966. (Box 34, Folder 17)
- P.I. Co. - Reports, Securities, Directors - Correspondence
  - “Del Monte Miscellaneous”. Entertainment account, payroll financial recapitulation, inventory return for special tax on wholesale liquor, (1915), (Dec. 31, 1913), (Jan. 1917). Dates: Dec. 1913 - Oct. 1917. (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - “Hotel Del Monte Financial Reports 1916 - 1917”. Monthly financial reports and balance sheets comparing each month of to the same month the previous year. (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - “Inventory - H.D.M. - P. G. Div. - M.C.W.W. - Feb. 1, 1919”. ie. Hotel Del Monte, Pacific Grove Division, and Monterey County Water Works. Haskin & Sells reports, dated 13/14/19. (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - “Sale of Monterey Peninsula Properties - ”. Financial analysis of sales., Feb. 1, 1919 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - “Original Cost of Monterey County Water Works”. Copies of original accounts from, 1883 and 1884. (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - “Monterey County Water Works”. Miscellaneous - decisions and general orders to public utilities from R.R. Comm. of Calif., table of water rates per cu. ft., resolution fixing the water rates details of water rights and rights-of-way acct., (1913 - 1914), Dates: 1906 - 1917. (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - “Southern Pacific Co. - Right-of-Way Pacific Grove” Correspondence, copy of deed, map, 1917. (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - “Pebble Beach Cottages, Wharf and Golf Course”. Financial reports: details of charges to cottages, statements of cost of wharf, details of charges for golf course improvements, dates: 1916 - 1917. (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - “Pacific Grove Miscellaneous”. Inventories, statement of payment due from guests and P.I. Co., journal entires, ledger accts., report of revenues., Dates: 1914 - 1915. (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - “Assignments - Monterey Peninsula Contracts”., Dates: 1910 - 1919. (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - “Del Monte Forest Camp”. Brochure and map, 1918. (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - “Pacific Grove Collections- ”. For every month there is a balance sheet and reports on accounts receivable, land department collections, land department journal entries., 1916 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - “Pacific Grove Collections- ”: Monthly reports and balance sheet., 1917 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - “Pacific Grove Collections- ”. Monthly reports and balance sheet., 1918 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - “Pacific Grove Collections ”. Monthly reports and balance sheet., 1919 (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - “Pacific Grove Collections, ”. Monthly reports and balance sheet., 1920-1921 (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - “Hotel Del Monte Collections - 1919”. Analysis of balance as of monthly reports of accounts receivable items collected, 1/31/19, Jan. - May 1919. (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - “Monterey Peninsula Contracts Data”. Personal correspondence and some P.I. Co. form letters re: contracts and deeds., Dates: Feb. 1915 - Aug. 1917. (Box 35, Folder 18)
  - “Monterey Peninsula Miscellaneous”. Various reports and information regarding Hotel Del Monte, Pacific Grove Hotel, real estate sale and property owned, 1910 - Aug. 1917. (Box 35, Folder 19)
  - “ - Plant Account Data”. Financial reports and data re: changes and improvements on the plants of various P.I. Co. Monterey Peninsula holdings., 1916 (Box 35, Folder 20)
  - “Pacific Grove - Sales Book Adjustment”. All data collected in adjusting Sale Book with the outstanding contracts, dates: 1911 - 1914. (Box 35, Folder 21)
  - “Weekly Statements of Cash Received - M.C.W.W. ”. Re: Monterey County Water Works., 1917 and 1918 (Box 35, Folder 22)
  - “Inventories ”. Hope Ranch, Rancho Del Monte, Santa Barbara Ranches, Pebble Beach Lodge, S.F. Office., 1917 and 1918 (Box 35, Folder 23)
  - “Income and Expenses - Hotel Del Monte”. On ledger sheets by the month, years, 1899 - 1914. (Box 35, Folder 24)
  - “Photographs of Houses at Pebble Beach”. (Box 35, Folder 25)
  - “Data Re: Work Done on Y.W.C.A. Property”. Bills, correspondence, reports, April 1913 - Aug. 1915. (Box 35, Folder 26)
  - “New York Office - 1918”. Journal abstracts for various months in (Box 35, Folder 27)
  - “New York Office - 1919”. Journal abstracts for various months in (Box 35, Folder 28)
  - “New York Office - Miscellaneous”. Pamphlet explaining N.Y. State income tax financial information on P.I. Co. (as of summary of N.Y. office profit and loss, (7/1/17), March 1916), 1914 - 1916. (Box 35, Folder 29)
  - “Alta Vista Tract - Maps and Blueprints”. Subdivision maps and blueprint plans of houses. (Box 35, Folder 30)
  - “Alta Vista Tract - Improvements Data”. Maps, correspondence with Billings and Meyering, investments and subdivisions specialists, estimated and actual statements of cost of improvements., Dates: Nov. 29, 1915 - Feb. 13, 1919. (Box 35, Folder 31)
  - “Alta Vista Tract - Miscellaneous”. Explanation of accounts, real estate sales schedules, correspondence with A.G. Wishon among others contracts for deeds of land around Fresno statements of disbursements and paid bills brochure for Alta Vista and map of central Calif. pointing out Fresno., (1914), (1914), (1917) (Box 35, Folder 32)
  - “Alta Vista Tract - Expenses Statements of A.G. Wishon, ”. Correspondence accompanying statements. Expenses incurred in up keep of tract., April 1914 to Jan. 1919 (Box 35, Folder 33)
  - “Intermational Railways of Central America”. Folder filled with booklets including deed of sale of Guatemala Central R.R. Co. to International Railways of Central America Int. Railways of Cent. Amer., mortgages to Empire Trust Co. and Equitable Trust Co. of N.Y. various Int. Railways of Cent. Amer. annual statements, (4/24/12), (5/1/12), 1918 - 1926. (Box 35, Folder 34)
  - “P.I. Co. Audit Reports ”. By Haskins and Sells., 1916-1922 (Box 35, Folder 35)
  - “Omnibus Deed - Chas. Crocker Heirs to Crocker Estate Co.”., 9/1/10. (Box 35, Folder 36)
  - “Ione Coal and Iron Co. - Statements to McKissick Cattle Co.”. Statements re: Ione Ranch, dated: Aug. 1917 - April 1918. (Box 35, Folder 37)
  - “Shepard Suit - Santa Barbara”. Correspondence, contracts for deeds, lease, map re: sale of land in Santa Barbara, Hope Ranch land, Dates: Aug. 1910 - July 1916. (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - “Castle Crag”. Cancelled checks and notation of “account”, (April - Sept. 1915) Jan. 1917. (Box 35, Folder 39)
  - “Affiliated Companies”. Balance sheets and inventories for: El Verano Villa Assn., Rocky Mtn. Merchantile Co., Guatemala Central R.R. Co., Capay Valley Land Co., and Oakland Water Front Co., Dates: 1912 - Mar 1917. (Box 35, Folder 40)
  - “Deferred Land Payments”. Listings through, Dec. 31, 1916. (Box 35, Folder 41)
  - “Rancho Del Monte”. Informal reports from H.R. Verrue to A.D. Shepard and S.F.B. Morse, (12/18/13) (6/21/15). (Box 35, Folder 42)
  - “Santa Barbara”. Report and analysis of profit and loss re: Santa Barbara Ranches, (12/31/16). (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - “Land Dept. - Miscellaneous”. List of contracts past due in Montague, (8/11/16). (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - “Statements of Account - G.M. Heckster, Hope Ranch, Las Positas Land Co., Laguna Blanca Water Co.”., Aug. 31, 1919. (Box 35, Folder 45)
  - “Macomber Log Cabin”. Inventory, balance sheet, correspondence., Dates: 1916 - 1921. (Box 35, Folder 46)
  - “Journal Entries - Balance Sheets etc. - S.F. ”., 1915-1916 (Box 35, Folder 47)
  - “Ione Coal and Iron Co. - Tax Papers”., 1909 - 1922. (Box 35, Folder 48)
  - “Ione Coal and Iron Co. - Sale at Ione Ranch”. Consents to option and sale of Ione C. & I. Co. from stockholders contract for deed to W.H. Moffat, H.G. Humphrey, and C.B. Henderson - also called the McKissick Cattle Co. and deed of trust to Stanford University, (April 1917), (March - April 1917) (Nov. 1921). (Box 35, Folder 49)
  - “Deeds - I.C. & I. Co.”. Re: Ione Coal and Iron Co., List of contents on folder, dates range: 1/3/05 - 8/25/17. (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - “Meeting Notices and Proxies - I.C. & I. Co.”. Directors' and stockholders' meetings Proxy of Stanford U. Board of Trustees, Jan. - Nov. 1921. (Nov. 1921). (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - “Estate Papers - I. C. & I. Co.”. Estates of Majorie Holland, Ellen Cotton, Chas. H. Tweed, and John B. Dahlgren., Dates: 1918 - 1921. (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - “Fuller Engineering Co. - Allentown Pa., Designing and Constructing Engineers”. Estimate to P.I. Co. for installing complete power plant for burning pulverized coal., Date: 3/13/17. (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - “Leases - I.C. & I. Co.”. List of contents on folder., Dates range: 10/24/14 - 11/13/16. (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - “Agreements - I.C. & I. Co.”. List of contents on folder., Dates range: 1/1/06 - 3/22/17. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - “Reports - T.M.C.W.W.”. ie. Monterey County Water Works. List of contens on folder., 1918. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - “Miscellaneous - T.M.C.W.W.”. List of contents on folder. Includes contract, quiet title decree, schedule, resolution, maps, data., Dates: 9/10/07 - 1/7/19. (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - “Monterey County Water Works - Miscellaneous Documents”. Includes report of original cost of M.C.W.W., copy of articles of incorporation copy of by-laws and amended by-laws, notices of meetings (stockholders and directors), reports of directors meetings. Original of Sec. of Stata's Certificate of M.C.W.W. -, (1905), Dates range: 10/21/05 - 10/5/31. 1907. (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - “Miscellaneous - I.C. & I. Co.”. List of contents, Includes reports, bills of sale, release of property, registered stock., dates: 8/3/09 - 2/8/17. (Box 36, Folder 10)
- The rest of Box #36 is filled with P.I. Co. deeds for quitclaims, all blank.
- Crocker-Huffman Correspondence - P.I. Co. Land Department -, 1922, 1918
  - “Index to Crocker-Huffman Correspondence- ”. Alphabetical by correspondent., 1922 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - “L.D. Van Horne”. Was General Superintendent of C-H Co., correspondence with S.F.B. Morse. (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - “E.M. Brown, ”. Office Manager of C-H Co. in Merced, correspondence with S.F.B. Morse., Oct. - Dec. (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - “E.M. Brown, ”., Jan. - Sept. (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - “Miscellaneous”. (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - “Christmas Bonuses and Contributions to Charity”. (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - “Merced Irrigation District and Miscellaneous”. (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - “La Paloma Right-of-Way, Exchequer Dam, Arena Lands”. All have to do with M.I.D. (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - “Cattle Purchases and Beef Sales”. (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - “Personnel”. Application, recommendations and memos between S.F.B. Morse and Van Horne re: openings with C-H. (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - “Real Estate Deals”. Sales, pruchases and trades. Discussed - no finalizations. (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - “Legal Documents”. Correspondence signed by E.M. Brown accompanying legal documents ie. deeds, assignment, reconveyances. Sent to S.F. for execution. (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - “Dry Creek Resevoir Project”. Includes map. (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - “Deeds and Reconveyances of Trust Deeds”, Some letters to S.F. requesting execution, also memos from S.F.B.M. notifying Merced of business deals having been finalized. (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - “Water System”. Re: water rights, royalties and up keep of system. (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - “Miscellaneous”. Dealing with sundry aspects of C-H business: reservoirs, slaughter-house and refridgeration, agriculture and so on. (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - “Deane Tract”. Part of C-H Co. holdings in Merced, up for sale. Map included. (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - “Merced Irrigation District - Rights-of-Way”. Conveyed to M.I. D. by C-H Co. (Box 37, Folder 18)
  - “Insurance Claims”. (Box 37, Folder 19)
  - “Sale of Fig Orchard”. (Box 37, Folder 20)
  - “Land Sale to W.W. Thomas”. Crocker Colony lots #138 and 139. (Box 37, Folder 21)
  - “Proposed Oil Lease - L.F. Giffen”. For Merced land, not finalized. (Box 37, Folder 22)
  - “Real Estate Trades - City Bldgs. for Undeveloped Merced Land”. Correspondence, sketches of bldgs., brochures, appraisals. Final deal with Donn & Williams. (Box 37, Folder 23)
  - “Monthly Livestock Tallies, ”., Dec. 1921 - March 1923 (Box 37, Folder 24)
- P.I. Co. Land Department begins here, files by city or township names arranged alphabetically. Files contain almost exclusively, correspondence but, there are some deeds, leases and maps. Everyting is, dated 1918.
  - “City of Alameda, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 25)
  - “Amsterdam, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 26)
  - “Anderson, Shasta County, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 27)
  - “Armora, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 28)
  - “Battle Mountain, Nevada”. (Box 37, Folder 29)
  - “Benson, Arizona”. (Box 37, Folder 30)
  - “Boulder Creek, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 31)
  - “Bowerbank, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 32)
  - “Butler, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 33)
  - “Capay Valley Land Co.”. (Box 37, Folder 34)
  - “Coalinga, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 35)
  - “Colton, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 36)
  - “Dinuba, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 37)
  - “Dunsmuir, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 38)
  - “El Verano, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 39)
  - “Exeter, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 40)
  - “Famosa, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 41)
  - “Firebaugh, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 42)
  - “Fowler, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 43)
  - “Fresno, Calif., ”., Sept. - Dec. (Box 37, Folder 44)
  - “Fresno, Calif., ”., May - August (Box 37, Folder 45)
  - “Fresno, Calif., ”., Jan. - April (Box 37, Folder 46)
  - “Galt, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 47)
  - “Gallatin, Tract, Red Bluff, Tehama County, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 48)
  - “Gridley, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - “Harford, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 50)
  - “Herndon, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 51)
  - “Hickman, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 52)
  - “Huron, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 53)
  - “Irrigosa, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 54)
  - “Ivesta, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 55)
  - “Kern County (Bakersfield), Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 56)
  - “Lemoore, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 57)
  - “Lindsay, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 58)
  - “Los Banos, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 59)
  - “Lovelock, Nevada”. (Box 37, Folder 60)
  - “Maxwell, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 61)
  - “Mendota, Wash.”. (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - “Merced, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 63)
  - “Modesto, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 64)
  - “Mojave, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 65)
  - “Montague, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 66)
  - “Montpelier, Stanislaus County, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 67)
  - “Nelson, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 68)
  - “Newhall, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 69)
  - “Newman, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 70)
  - “Nord, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 71)
  - “Nord, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 72)
  - “Orland, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 73)
  - “Reedley, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 74)
  - “Reno, Nevada”. (Box 37, Folder 75)
  - “Ryer, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 76)
  - “Sanger, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 77)
  - “San Miguel, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 78)
  - “D.G. Van Dyke, Dagget, Calif.”. (Box 37, Folder 79)
  - “SW1/4 Sect. 1, T17s, R20E, O.W. Johnson and R.A. Newell”. Land sold to Johnson, Jan. - Feb. 1918. (Box 37, Folder 80)
- Land Department Contents and format similar to previous land department files., 1918 and 1924. (38-1 to 38-18 dated 1918).
  - “Santa Margarita, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - “Saticoy, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - “Sheep's Island, S.F., Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - “Sisson, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - “Tehachapi, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - “Tracy, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - “Traver, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - “Tulare, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - “Wadsworth, Nevada”. (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - “Waterford, Calif.”. Waterford Irrigation District, Waterford Land & Developement Co. (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - “Wells, Nevada”. (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - “Westley, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - “Tahoe, Calif.”. Lake Tahoe Fire Protection Assc. (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - “Misc. - Quitclaim in Fresno County, Winnsmucca, Nevada, Santa Barbara, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - “Taxes, ”., Oct. - Dec. (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - “Taxes, ”., Jan. - Sept. (Box 38, Folder 16)
  - “M.V. Gregg Tract, Marysville, Calif.”. (Box 38, Folder 17)
  - “Correspondence from H.R. Verrue”. P.I. Co. employee, reporting of accounts or remitting collections he has made. (Box 38, Folder 18)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. and Misc.-1919 and 1920”., Oct. - Dec. 1918 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., July - Sept. 1918 (Box 38, Folder 20)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., April - June 1918 (Box 38, Folder 21)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., Jan. - March 1918. (Box 38, Folder 22)
  - “Amsterdam, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - “Benson, Arizona ”., 1922-1924 (Box 38, Folder 24)
  - “Biggs, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 25)
  - “Boulder Creak, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 38, Folder 26)
  - “Capay, Calif. ”. Guinda Colony Tract., 1922 and 1923 (Box 38, Folder 27)
  - “Colfax, Wash. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 38, Folder 28)
  - “Colton, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 38, Folder 29)
  - “Cottonwood, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 30)
  - “Cross Landing, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 31)
  - “Delano, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 38, Folder 32)
  - “Delta, Shasta County, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 38, Folder 33)
  - “Dinuba, Calif. ”., 1922-1925 (Box 38, Folder 34)
  - “Dunsmuir, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 38, Folder 35)
  - “Elko, Nevada ”., 1922-1924 (Box 38, Folder 36)
  - “El Verano, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 38, Folder 37)
  - “Exeter, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 38, Folder 38)
  - “Famosa, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 38, Folder 39)
  - “Firebaugh, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 38, Folder 40)
  - “Fowler, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 38, Folder 41)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”. Alta Vista Tract., Oct. - Dec. 1924 (Box 38, Folder 42)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., June - Sept. 1924 (Box 38, Folder 43)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., March - May 1924 (Box 38, Folder 44)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Feb. 1924 (Box 38, Folder 45)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Jan. 1924 (Box 38, Folder 46)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Oct. - Dec. 1923 (Box 38, Folder 47)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., July - Oct. 1923 (Box 38, Folder 48)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Jan. - June 1923 (Box 38, Folder 49)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Nov. - Dec. 1922 (Box 38, Folder 50)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., June - Oct. 1922 (Box 38, Folder 51)
  - “Fresno, Calif. ”., Jan. - May 1922 (Box 38, Folder 52)
- Land Department (end) - Land Department (begin), 1924 1917
  - “Galt, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - “Goshen, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - “Hanford, Calif. ”., 1923 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - “Herndon, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - “Hickman, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - “Ingomar, Calif. ”., 1923 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - “Jameson, Calif. ”., 1923 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - “Kern County (Bakersfield), Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - “Lemoore, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - “Lethent, Calif. ”. J.P. Lemon, Hanford, Calif., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - “Lindsay, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - “Maxwell, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - “Mendota, Wash. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - “Merced, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - “Modesto, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - “Mojave, Calif. ”., 1922-1924. (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - “Monson, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - “Montague, Siskiyou County, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - “Newhall, Los Angeles, County, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 19)
  - “Oakland, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 20)
  - “Terrace, Utah ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 39, Folder 21)
  - “Palermo, Calif. ”., 1923 (Box 39, Folder 22)
  - “Porterville, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 23)
  - “Reedley, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 24)
  - “Reno, Nevada ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 39, Folder 25)
  - “Rio Bravo, Calif. ”. Elizabeth C. Houghton., 1923 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 26)
  - “Ryer, Calif. ”. California Hotel v. Elizabeth Ina Joy; C.W. Croop, attny., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 27)
  - “Sanger, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 28)
  - “San Miguel, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 29)
  - “Santa Margarita, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 30)
  - “Saticoy, Calif. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 31)
  - “Sissom, Calif. 1922”. Letter to Hubert Works, Postmaster General from Chas. Wheeler, Protesting a name change for the town and giving a history of the place., 9/2/22. (Box 39, Folder 32)
  - “Stanley, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 33)
  - “Stevens, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 34)
  - “Taupusa, Calif. ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 35)
  - “Tehachapi, Kern County, Calif. ”., 1923 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 36)
  - “Tracy, Calif. ”., 1923 (Box 39, Folder 37)
  - “Traver, Tulare County, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 38)
  - “Tulare, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 39)
  - “Truckee, Nevada, County, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1923 (Box 39, Folder 40)
  - “Wadsworth, Nevada ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 41)
  - “Waterford, Calif. ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 42)
  - “Wells, Nevada ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 43)
  - “Wyble Orchard, Kern County, Calif. ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 44)
  - “Winnemucca, Nevada ”., 1924 (Box 39, Folder 45)
  - “Nevada Property Titles and Taxes ”., 1922 and 1924 (Box 39, Folder 46)
  - “Re: Title - S.P. Co. to Robert Gillis ”., 1922 (Box 39, Folder 47)
  - “Taxes, 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 48)
  - “Oakland Water Front Co. ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 49)
  - “New York Properties ”., 1922-1924 (Box 39, Folder 50)
- Land Department, 1917
  - “Alameda, Calif.” (Box 39, Folder 51)
  - “Amsterdam, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 52)
  - “Armona, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 53)
  - “Battle Mountain, Nevada”. (Box 39, Folder 54)
  - “Benson, Arizona”. (Box 39, Folder 55)
  - “Boulder Creek, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 56)
  - “Bowerbank, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 57)
  - “Buttonwillow, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 58)
  - “Cando, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 59)
  - “Capay Valley, Calif. ”., July - Dec. (Box 39, Folder 60)
  - “Capay Valley, Calif. ”., Jan. - June (Box 39, Folder 61)
  - “Coalinga, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 62)
  - “Collis, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 63)
  - “Colton, Calif.”. (Box 39, Folder 64)